Raúl Esteban Burró Cespedes

Email: rauleburro@gmail.com

Nationality: Paraguayan/Spanish

Profile

Software engineer with +8 years on the market, working with frontend and mobile technologies, such as Flutter, React, and React Native, experience deployment productions apps on the AppStore, Google Play Store and cloud. Fast learner and autodidact, proactive and proficient.

Able to effectively collaborate as part of a productive team, providing reliable solutions to problems, and willing to create a comfortable work environment. I am excited to continue strengthening my career and increasing my skills.

Technologies

Flutter, React Native, React, Nodejs, Google Cloud Platform, Kubernetes, Docker, Digital Ocean, Git, Github, Jira.

Skills

- Making the right choice and having sound knowledge of our tools.
- Keep the code clean and able to adapt.
- · Great problem solver.
- Efficient trough optimization
- Aim for success at the start.
- · Self-evaluate along the way
- Full-cycle software development using Agile methodologies (SCRUM).

Experience

Frontend/Mobile Developer and SRE/DevOps

Bucksapp | Sep 2021 - Present

- I start maintaining the react native app and developing new features using best practices and redux for state management.
- I start to develop the new app from scratch using Next.js with redux and sagas, implementing unit and integration tests, and deploying with docker.

Co-Founder

Bellbird | Jan 2020 - Present

- I founded this company in 2020 to develop technology solutions for our clients.
- My first client, PuntoFarma, is the most extensive pharmacy in Paraguay. I developed for then a mobile app using flutter 2.0 with null safety, flutter_bloc for state management and connected their oracle backend using an intermediate backend written in node.js using express.js framework. Today the app manages +9k users per day with +70k downloads on Android and +1k on IOs.
- In 2021, I hired more people for my Team, and I started managing the company as a CEO and manage Team.

- In September of 2021, I saw the company could be auto administrate, and I decided to leave my position as a CEO to dedicate my time to work as a software engineer and DevOps engineer.
- I am still on the board, but I don't need to stay operative in the company.

Fullstack software engineer / Tech Lead

Softec SRL | Sep 2016 - Jan 2020

- I Start working with Django apps using javascript for the front, implementing testing using Selenium.
- In 2017, I started working on an Uber-like app called MUV with two apps in Android, one for drivers and one for clients, and two apps in IOS with Swift. And a backend in laravel.
- I lead a team of 3 developers until the app's release in 2018.
- In 2018, after the app's release, my Team started working on version 2 of the app MUV. We used React Native for the app, React for the front, and Node for the backend.
- After that, in 2019, I was promoted to Tech Lead of the company and started to manage four teams with different skills using Gitlab workflow.

FullStack Developer

Freelance | Jan 2014 - Sep 2016

• I started my professional life in 2012 as a freelancer doing some projects using Django as a whole stack framework, an app with Android framework, and many websites.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in computer science, Universidad Nacional de Asunción, San Lorenzo, Paraguay

Languages

- English (Intermediate)
- Spanish (Native)

Platforms

Linux, macOS, Windows